Now that we learned how to load components, let's add more routes here to load different components like new
imdi, bileenleri nasl ykleyeceimizi reneceiz. Bileeni yklerken, Apotheker' oaltp imdi yeni yaz aramak
post component. So I'll simply duplicate my path here and now looking for new post and here we could
ve burada tam da kaldrmak iin farkl bileenleri yklemek iin buraya daha fazla rota
also remove exact because maybe we want to handle all routes starting with /new-post with that
ekleyelim; nk belki btn yollar Eik izgi ve bununla birlikte mesaj yazarsn ya da sadece
or you leave exact if you really only want to handle /new-post and not
eik izgiyi ilemek istiyorsan tabii ki eik izgiyi kaldrmak istemiyorsan
/new-post one
tam olarak terk et.
And now here, the component of course is not posts but a component we have to import,
Ve ite burada elbette bileen deil ileti almak zorunda olduumuz bir bileen.
we have to import new post from of course /new-post new post/newposts.js just like this.
Yeni mesaj tabii ki bu ekilde almamz gerekiyor, bunun gibi yeni yazlan yeni yaynlar slash yapalm.
Now let's grab new post here and add it like this, NewPost, save this.
imdi burada yazlan bir Graben ve bunu dzenleyen bu yeni yaz gibi dzenleyin.
Now you see we see the posts here
imdi buradaki yaynlar gryoruz.
but if I click on new post, we see the new post component and not our posts, this
Ancak, yeni mesaj tklarsam, mesajlarmda deil de yeni yayn bileenini grrz.
is already showing you how routing works.
Zaten ynlendirme ileminin nasl yapldn gsteriyor.
Right now our application has an issue though, we can click these links
u anda bavurumuzun bir sorunu var, ancak bu balantlar tklayabiliriz.
they are normal anchor tags but each time our application actually reloads, as can see if you watch the
Normal bir apa metnidirler, ancak sizi tekrar izlediinizi grp grebileceimiz her zaman uygulamanz yeniden
reload
yklenir.
icon next to the URL bar.
Senin ya da Albar'n yanna duyabiliyorum.
Now this is not a problem here
imdi burada sorun deil mi?
but theoretically a reloading application means that your javascript code is starting anew and therefore
Ancak teorik olarak tekrar yklenen bir uygulama, javascript kodunun yeni balatld anlamna gelir ve
all previous application state is lost.
bu nedenle nceki tm uygulama durumlar kaybolur.
This is rarely what you want in your react application, as long as the user is navigating around in it,
Gerekten de, kullancnn iinde dolat srece tekrar uygulama uygulamanz istediin ey buydu.
you want to not reload the page, you want to just re-render the page in the parts where it needs to be
Sayfay yalnzca yeni sayfa gibi grnmesi iin nceden oluturulmas gereken ksmlarda yeniden oluturmak
re-rendered to look like the new page.
istediiniz sayfay yeniden yklemek istemiyorsunuz.
So we need to change to behaviour so that we don't have a normal link here which reloads the page but
Dolaysyla, sayfay yeniden ykleyen normal bir balantya sahip olmadmz, ancak bunun yerine sayfann yeniden
that instead we prevent the rebuilding of the page and let react router only re-render parts of the
oluturulmasn engelleyip ynlendiriciyi yeniden ynlendirmesine izin vermek iin davrana gememiz gerekiyor, yalnzca domun blmleri iin yeniden
dom or tell react what to re-render to be precise that needs to be re-rendered.
okunabilir veya yeniden syleyebiliriz - yeniden okunacak veya kesin olarak gsterilmesi gereken ey, yeniden oluturulmas gerekiyor.
So let's in the next lecture find out how we can make sure that we stay inside of our application and
Bir sonraki dersimizde, uygulamanzn iinde kalmamz ve srekli tekrar yklememizi nasl
don't reload it all the time.
salayacamz renelim.